# Daniel Tolczyk

Starting my technical career in the United States Marine Corp as a Cryptologic Linguist, I fell in love with technology. After my enlistment I went to school for cybersecurity and information assurance and studied front-end development and general programming. Through an internship I became an applications programmer and later an information security specialist at Motorola.

Chicago,IL (312) 859-9002 daniel.tolczyk@gmail.com

#### **EXPERIENCE**

### **Motorola Solutions** — Information Security Specialist

May 2021 - PRESENT

- Primary cybersecurity expert acting as a liaison between multiple product teams and cybersecurity teams.
- Participated in Secure Design Reviews and auditing of STIG requirements for 2 product releases.
- Managed the scanning and tracking of third-party open-source software using Mend, Tenable, OWASP ZAP, and manual internal tools.
- Responsible for the creation and maintenance of customer-facing documentation regarding software versioning and open-source licenses.
- Configured logging to meet cybersecurity requirements for multiple back-end components.
- Wrote and updated scripts to manage the creation of administrative accounts.

## **Spirit Inc** — Cloud Security Analyst

May 2019 - August 2019

- Conducted Risk Assessment's in preparation for SOC2 audits.
- Implemented initial security program by creating new security and backup plan policies.
- Identified and responded to minor security incidents with remediation through personally training employees on solutions.

## **Park Tower Senior Housing, LP**— IT Specialist and User Technical Support

May 2018 - May 2019

- Upgraded and maintained computer security on systems used to access sensitive personal information.
- Improved computer performance, maintaining programs and skills needed for life-betterment and support of clientele.
- Led training on software, web applications, and security weekly

#### **SKILLS**

Vulnerability Management
Vulnerability Detection
Tenable Nessus
Jira and Confluence
Team Management

#### Certifications

ISC2- SSCP: This certificate demonstrates my advanced technical skills and knowledge to implement, monitor and administer IT infrastructure using security best practices.

CompTIA- Pentest+: This certificate demonstrates my ability to build and plan comprehensive vulnerability assessments and manage security with a heavy focus on compliance.

CompTIA- CySA+: This certificate demonstrates my ability to leverage intelligence and threat detection techniques, identify and address vulnerabilities and works towards being proactive with capturing and monitoring of network traffic

for residents.

## **United States Marine Corps** — Cryptologic Linguist

September 2004 - November 2009

- Monitored, transcribed, and translated intercepted target communications.
- Performed analysis and exploitation of designated foreign communications.
- Installed, operated, and performed preventive maintenance of intercept equipment.

### findings.

CompTIA - Security+: This certificate demonstrates my ability to create access controls and identity management, write compliance and operational security documents and find threats and vulnerabilities within a company's network.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Westerns Governors University** — B.S Cybersecurity and Information Assurance

2019 -2021

WGU's B.S of Cybersecurity and Information Assurance degree reinforced and taught the following. Data management, web and cloud security, secure system design and hacking countermeasures.

## Code Platoon — Full Stack Web Development

2020 -2020

A bootcamp made for veterans, I studied full stack development. I learned python and javascript with PostgreSQL, git and Github. This has allowed me to understand SSDLC and build robust security plans for software engineering.

## **Spokane Falls Community College** — Associates of Arts

2016 -2018

To further my education and build a career I spent time gaining an Associate of arts, I took additional classes to earn my degree. Those classes are the following. Linux, Network Management, IT Ethics, Network security, Ethical Hacking, Endpoint security and Project Management.

#### **LANGUAGES**

Arabic